CLARANCE LIBERISTE NTWARI

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | TYPESCRIPT & NODE.IS



ABOUT

RWANDA

LIBERINTWARI@GMAIL.COM

CLARANCELIBERI

■ CLARA

PROFICIENT LANGUAGES/FRAMEW ORK

PROFICIENT

TYPESCRIPT NODE.JS VUE.JS VITEST **CYPRESS** GOLANG

DATABASE

PROFICIENT

REDIS MONGODB MYSQL **POSTGRESQL**

OTHER LANGUAGES

WORKING

GOLANG GIN **JAVA NEST.JS**

DEVOPS

PROFICIENT

DOCKER **ANSIBLE JENKINS GITLAB** GCP AWS

METHODOLOGIES

AGILE

PROFICIENT

SUMMARY

A software developer with over 7 years of experience developing modern web technologies solutions and has a passion for creativity, dedication, and ongoing personal growth. Has worked in small startups of 4 to large companies of 150 coworkers. Has led team of 10 in Agile methodologies and a track record of working remotely for 3 years, with a strong emphasis on team collaboration and efficient results

EXPERIENCE

BRITISH PETROLEUM (BP)

SENIOR FULLSTACK(GO & REACT) ENGINEER

07/2021 - 01/2023

Delivered significant contributions to different teams, improved user experiences, managed monorepo architecture, implemented CI/CD pipelines, and helped keep track of action logs on the Superfleet platform.

- Created an audit log microservice in golang gin that records all user actions for traceability, In audit log team.
- Developed a notification microservice in golang gin that handles all notifications for the SuperFleet platform, the notification well streamlined in kafka and redis.
- Created micro-frontends with Webpack module federation and vue.js, which improved the developer experience by 70%.
- Created different components under the Atomic Design principle and Storybook while making the BP design system, reducing component dependency by 35%.
- Wrote Regression and Unit tests of the components in the BP design System.

HUNTERSOFBOOK

FULL STACK ENGINEER

Improved frontend development and user engagement at HuntersOfBook through storybook UI components and WYSIWYG editor.

- Created Component presentation with storybook, which improved Developer experience by 15%.
- Wrote unit test and integration test respecting TDD with Jest and testing-
- Built end-to-end APIs using Nest.js, PostgreSQL, Prisma, and Graphql.
- Developed a powerful WYSIWYG editor using Vue.js, an editor that made content writing smooth and faster with a 45% increase in efficiency for users.
- Wrote GitHub Action scripts for PRs, automating PR validations and automatic deployment, speeding up the normal manual process from 15mins to 55 secs.

STUNNITY

01/2018 - 05/2020

04/2020 - 06/2022

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Led a team and implemented features at Stunnity through analysis, design, mentorship, and efficient deployment using CI/CD pipeline.

- Led software analysis and design by making Software Requirement Specification (SRS), data dictionaries, DFD, and user use cases.
- Setup Gitlab Enterprise server, Jenkins, Tomcat, PM2, Docker, and Kubernetes for Go, Node.js, and vue.js app CI/CD.
- Integrated 4 backend microservices and Frontend on Gitlab pipeline and
- Led a team of 10, Reviewed code and taught the team how to use modern software methodologies.
- Implemented different features on live streaming calls and chat with Node.js
- Wrote component and e2e tests using the react-testing library and Cypress.

03/2015 - 01/2018 **KURIOUS LTD**

SCRUM KANBAN ATOMIC DESIGN BEM

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH (PROFESSIONAL)

FULL STACK ENGINEER

Developed tools for video and textual materials for students and a real-time messaging service for communication between students and teachers, improving the platform's front-end, making the platform more competitive with Coursera and Edx.

- Developed and led software analysis and design process, resulting in the successful creation of over 20 Software Requirement Specification (SRS) documents, data dictionaries, DFD diagrams, and user use cases.
- Setup Gitlab Enterprise server, Jenkins, Tomcat, PM2, Docker, and Kubernetes for Java, Node.js, and Vue.js app CI/CD.
- Implemented DevOps workflows on Digital Ocean, speeding CI/CD process by 30%
- Developed Chat, Live Stream, and Students Forum modules, resulting in a 50% increase in user engagement and communication, utilizing technologies such as webRTC, socket.io, Vue.js, and Kurento.

VOLUNTEER

FUTURE SKILLS BOOTCAMP

12/2019 - 12/2019

WEB DEVELOPMENT MENTOR

Taught programming concepts to 350 children under 18 during a two week program.

- Covered five skills including HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP, and SQL.
- Guided and facilitated students in presenting final projects on demo day.
- Facilitated students in designing web pages within 7 days, helping to foster competitive programming and creative thinking skills.

EDUCATION

RWANDA CODING ACADEMY

02/2019 - 07/2022

ASSOCIATES DEGREE IN SOFTWARE PROGRAMMING & EMBEDDED SYSTEMS